Let's start by explaining what is TensorFlow.
TensorFlowとは
TensorFlow is an open source,
数値処理用の 高パフォーマンスな
It's not just about machine learning.
機械学習の分野だけでなく
It's about any numeric computation.
あらゆる数値処理で使われます
Infact,, people have used TensorFlow for all kinds of GPU computing.
実際 にあらゆる種類の GPUコンピューティングで使われてきました
For example, you can use TensorFlow to solve partial differential equations.
たとえば 偏微分方程式を 解くことができますが
These are useful in domains like fluid dynamics.
これは流体力学などで役立ちます
Tensorflow as a numeric program library is appealing,
数値プログラムライブラリとしても 魅力的です
because you can write your competition code in a high level language,
Pythonなどの高水準言語で 複雑なコードを書いて
The way TensorFlow works is that you create a directed acyclic graph, a DAG.
TensorFlowでは 有向非巡回グラフ（DAG）を作成して
To represent your computation.
コンピュテーションを表します
In this schematic, the nodes represent mathematical operations.
この図でノードは 数学演算を表します
Things like adding, subtracting, multiplying et cetera.
足し算、引き算、掛け算などです
Also more complex functions.
もっと複雑な関数もあります
Here for example you see soft max matrix multiplication.
たとえばソフトマックス 行列乗算です
These are all mathematical operations that are
これらはすべて
Connecting the nodes in the DAG are the edges,
DAG内のノードを 繋いでいるのがエッジ
the input and the output of mathematical operations.
つまり数学演算の入力と出力です
The edges represent arrays of data.
エッジはデータの配列を表します
Essentially the result of computing across
基本的に エントロピーでの計算結果が
entropy is one of the three inputs to the bias add
bias add演算の3つの入力の一つとなり
operation and the output of the bias and
bias add演算の出力が
operation is sent along the matrix multiplication operation,
行列乗算演算に送られます
matmul in the diagram.
この図のMatMulです
The other input to matmul,
MatMulへの他の入力として
you need to input your matrix multiplication.
行列乗算を入力する必要があります
The other input is a variable, the weight.
もう一つの入力は重み変数です
So where does the name TensorFlow come from.
TensorFlowという名前の由来は何でしょうか
In math a simple number like three or five is called a scalar.
数学では基数が スカラーと呼ばれます
A vector is a one dimensional array of such numbers.
ベクトルはスカラーからなる 1次元配列です
In physics a vector is something magnitude and direction,
物理学では 規模や方向を表しますが
but in computer science we've used vector to mean 1D arrays.
コンピュータサイエンスでは 1次元配列を意味します
A two-dimensional array is a matrix,
2次元の配列は行列です
but the three-dimensional array,
そして 3次元の配列は
we just call it a 3D tensor.
3Dテンソルと呼ばれます
So scalar, vector, matrix 3D tensor,
つまり スカラー、ベクトル、行列、3Dテンソル
4D tensor et cetera.
4Dテンソル ... と続きます
A tensor is an n dimensional array of data.
テンソルとはn次元のデータ配列です
So your data in TensorFlow, they are tensors.
TensorFlowのデータはテンソルで
They flow through the directed acyclic graph, hence TensorFlow.
DAGの中を流れていくので この名前になったのです